careonecredit.com 2011-12-22

# Privacy and Security

Print 

Effective Date: 8/25/2010 

This CareOne Website is owned and hosted by 3C Incorporated ("3Ci" or "we") for us and for licensees of the CareOneSM service mark. We are located at 8930 Stanford Boulevard, Columbia, Maryland 21045 and can be contacted via email at [customerservice@careonecredit.com](mailto:customerservice@careonecredit.com). We respect the privacy of the individuals accessing/using ("Users") this Website. 

We license the CareOneSM service mark to these debt relief agencies ("CCA's") that offer the CareOneSM brand of credit counseling services:

  * Consumer Education Services, Inc. (CESI)  
3700 Barrett Drive   
Raleigh, NC 27609-7248  
1-888-419-2374  
cesisupport@careonecredit.com  
CESI also administers Clarion Credit Management and Debt Management Group accounts  
View the Consumer Education Services, Inc. (CESI) Privacy Policy.  

  * CareOne Services, Inc.  
P.O. Box 6971  
Columbia, MD 21045-6971  
1-800-227-3123  
customercare@careonecredit.com  
View the CareOne Services, Inc. Privacy Policy. 
  * CareOne Services of California, Inc.   
8880 Rio San Diego Drive, Suite 800,  
San Diego, CA 92108  
1-800-227-3123  
customercare@careonecredit.com  
View the CareOne Services, Inc. Privacy Policy. 

We also license the CareOneSM service mark to the following national law firm which offers legal services to consumers, including negotiation of clients' debts, and is supported by CareOneSM technology:

  * Persels & Associates  
29 West Susquehanna Avenue  
Suite 400  
Towson, MD 21204  
1-866-939-PALAW (7252)  
View the Persels & Associates [Privacy Policy](http://www.perselsandassociates.com/privacy_policy.html).  

Information is collected on our Website on behalf of each of these licensees ("Counselors") so that potential customers and clients may engage the services of the Counselors and customers may receive services. Information also is collected on our behalf. This Privacy Policy applies to 3Ci and also applies to all activities that occur on this Website for customers of the CCA's and clients of Persels & Associates. The privacy policies of the Counselors also apply to customer information collected for the Counselors.

This Privacy Policy governs the Website and explains how your personal information is collected on our Website, how your information is protected, and the choices you have concerning the use of such information. Please read this Privacy Policy carefully. This Privacy Policy may be amended from time to time. We will post any changes here. Please refer back to this Privacy Policy on a regular basis. 

**TRUSTe CERTIFICATION**  

3Ci Incorporated is a Participant in the TRUSTe Privacy Seal Program. TRUSTe is an independent organization whose mission is to advance privacy and trust in the networked world. As this Website wants to demonstrate its commitment to your privacy, it has agreed to disclose its information practices and have its privacy practices monitored for compliance by TRUSTe.

If you have questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy, you should first contact us at [customercare@careonecredit.com](mailto:customercare@careonecredit.com). If you do not receive acknowledgment of your inquiry, or if your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, you should then contact TRUSTe at <http://www.truste.org/consumers/watchdog_complaint.php>. TRUSTe will then serve as a liaison with the Website to resolve your concerns.

By displaying the TRUSTe trust mark, we have agreed to notify you of the following:

  * What information about you is collected on this Website? 
  * Where and when is information collected on this Website (including through the use of cookies and web beacons)? 
  * Does this Website collect information from children under 13 years of age? 
  * What does this Website do with the information it collects? 
  * When does this Website disclose information to third parties? 
  * Does this Privacy Policy apply when you link to other Websites? 
  * Is the information collected on this Website secure? 
  * What choices do you have regarding the collection, disclosure and distribution of Personally Identifiable Information? 
  * Can you update or correct your Personally Identifiable Information? 
  * How will you know if there are any changes to this Privacy Policy?
  * Who do you contact if I have any privacy questions?

## BBBONLINE INVOLVEMENT NOTIFICATION

We participate in the Council of Better Business Bureau's BBBOnLine Privacy Program, and comply with all BBBOnLine Privacy standards. By participating in the Council of Better Business Bureau's BBBOnLine Privacy Program, we have made a commitment to meet the program's strict requirements regarding how we treat your information and have it verified by BBBOnLine. Further information about this program and its dispute resolution process is available at [http://www.bbbonline.org](http://www.bbbonline.org/).

## WHAT INFORMATION ABOUT YOU IS COLLECTED ON THIS WEBSITE?

This Website collects two types of information: Personally Identifiable Information and non-Personally Identifiable Information (see Section on Web Beacons).

## Personally Identifiable Information

Personally Identifiable Information is information that identifies you and allows you to enroll in debt management and debt settlement programs with the CCA's and to request legal representation offered by Persels & Associates through this Website ("Services"). Personally Identifiable Information also permits you to become a registered User of this Website. During the online process a wide variety of personal and financial data is collected by the Counselors. Such Personally Identifiable Information may include:

  * Debt Information (Credit Card / Loan Account Numbers & Balances) 
  * Personal Information (Social Security Number, Address, Phone, Email, Salary, Pay Period, Employer, Occupation) 
  * Demographic Information (Age, Birth Date, Gender) 
  * Budget Information (Assets, Monthly Expenses, Other Income)

This information is stored to use in enrolling Users for Services and in providing Services to Users. The Counselors and we may use the data for Users who do not complete the online enrollment process for internal analysis and to contact the Users to provide information about the Services. This information is not shared with any other party.

## DOES OUR WEBSITE COLLECT INFORMATION FROM CHILDREN UNDER 13 YEARS OF AGE?

We are committed to protecting the privacy of children. Our Website is not designed for or directed to children under the age of 13. Personally Identifiable Information from any person we actually know is under the age of 13 is not collected. We urge all parents or guardians to participate in their children's exploration of the Internet, and to teach their children about protecting their personal information while online.

## WHAT DOES OUR WEBSITE DO WITH THE INFORMATION IT COLLECTS?

In general, 3Ci uses the information collected on our Website to help us understand who uses our Website and how it is used, to personalize your online experience, and to improve our Website. 

If you enter your email address, name and phone number, and ask for more information, we may use your information to send you a welcoming email, electronic newsletters, contact you about products, services, information and news that may be of interest to you, and provide you with targeted feedback. 

In addition, if you become a registered User of this Website, we may use your information to send you an email confirming your User name and password.

If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about our site, we will ask you for your friend's name and email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site. 3Ci Incorporated stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email and tracking the success of our referral program.

Your friend may contact us at [customercare@careonecredit.com](mailto:customercare@careonecredit.com) to request that we remove this information from our database.

This Website offers community boards, blogs, and chat rooms. You should be aware that any Personally Identifiable Information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other Users of these forums, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the Personally Identifiable Information you choose to submit in these forums.

In addition, if you identify yourself to us by sending us an email with questions or comments, we may use your information (including Personally Identifiable Information) to respond to your questions or comments, and we may file your questions or comments for future reference.

We may also use the information gathered on our Website to perform statistical analysis of User behavior or to evaluate and improve our online services.

The Counselors may use the information gathered on the Website to analyze and evaluate issues relating to the Services provided to you, enrollment behavior and credit education for internal purposes only or to assist you in your debt reduction efforts.

Users who join the Website's online community, participate in contests, and/or provide testimonial statements are required to consent to the use of their posts/emails and Personally Identifiable Information in our marketing materials (see Terms of Use). If you wish to rescind or opt-out of this participation, you may contact us directly at [customercare@careonecredit.com](mailto:customercare@careonecredit.com) with this request.

## Opt-out Policy

If you prefer that we do not send you email communications, you may opt-out of those services, that is, you may direct us not to use your email address as part of our marketing efforts. If you wish to opt-out of email communications, you may do so by emailing [customercare@careonecredit.com](mailto:customercare@careonecredit.com), or by replying to an existing email with your request to be removed from the mailing list or click [here](http://mycareone.careonecredit.com/MyProfile/Subscriptions.aspx). 

## WHEN DOES OUR WEBSITE DISCLOSE INFORMATION TO THIRD PARTIES?

Personally identifiable information about you as well as email address will be disclosed to third parties only as described in the Gramm Leach Bliley Act Privacy Notice of the CCA that will administer the services provided to you.

To review the full Privacy Notice of each Counselor for all of the details and directions on how to "opt out" of information sharing by the CCA's click [here](http://www.careonecredit.com/about-us/service-providers.aspx). 

3Ci does not share, sell, rent or trade Personally Identifiable Information with third parties for their promotional purposes.

## DOES THIS PRIVACY POLICY APPLY WHEN I LINK TO OTHER WEBSITES?

This Website contains links to other Websites not owned or operated by us (for example, if you "click" on a Counselor link, you will likely be taken off our Website). We will attempt to make it obvious to you when you leave our Website and enter these Websites by opening a new browser or otherwise notifying you that you are leaving our Website. However, please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such Websites. We encourage you to be aware when our Website links to other Websites and to read the privacy policies or statements of each and every Website. This Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected by our Website.

## IS THE INFORMATION COLLECTED ON THIS WEBSITE SECURE?

We want your information (including Personally Identifiable Information and email address) to remain as secure as possible. We strive to provide secure transmission of your information from your computer to our servers through industry-standard techniques. To help ensure the integrity and privacy of the Personally Identifiable Information you provide via the Internet, we use Secured Socket Layer (SSL) encryption technology in transmitting such Personally Identifiable Information over the Internet to our servers. We secure the Personally Identifiable Information you provide on servers located in controlled, secure environments, protected from unauthorized access, use, or alteration. Only employees who need access to your information to perform a specific task or function are granted access to such information. No personal data is ever stored on our web servers. Sensitive information is encrypted within our database, to ensure internal security. In addition, all of our employees must abide by this Privacy Policy and are kept up-to-date on security practices. Any employee who violates this Privacy Policy is subject to disciplinary action, up to and including termination.

Notwithstanding the above commitments to protect your information (including Personally Identifiable Information) from loss, misuse or alteration by third parties, you should be aware that there is always some risk involved in transmitting information over the Internet. There is also some risk that others could find a way to thwart our security systems. As a result, while we strive to protect your information, we cannot ensure or warrant the security and privacy of any information you transmit to us, and you do so at your own risk.

## WHAT CHOICES DO I HAVE REGARDING THE COLLECTION, DISCLOSURE AND DISTRIBUTION OF PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION?

You may "opt out" of sharing your Personally Identifiable Information with affiliated and non-affiliated companies as explained in the Privacy Notices of the CCA's. To review the full Privacy Notice of each CCA for all of the details and directions on how to "opt out" click [here](http://mycareone.careonecredit.com/MyProfile/Subscriptions.aspx). 

Persels & Associates does not divulge your Personally Identifiable Information to anyone without your consent, except in very limited circumstances that require an attorney to divulge confidential information. In most jurisdictions, this is limited to a reasonable belief by the attorney that his or her client is about to commit an act that will result in death or serious bodily injury to another human being. To view Persels & Associates' full Privacy Notice click View the Persels & Associates [here](http://www.perselsandassociates.com/privacy_policy.html).

## CAN I CORRECT MY PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION?

You can always contact 3Ci to update, correct or delete your Personally Identifiable Information and email address or change your preferences with respect to communications and other information you receive from us by calling Customer Services at 1-800-699-5688. Such updates, corrections and deletions will not have any effect on the data that is maintained by the Counselors in connection with the Services. 

Current customers of the Counselors with online access to their Services can view, update or change their personal, contact and occupational information by selecting the Member Login navigation link off the Website home page, or by contacting Customer Service at 1-800-699-5688. You may also change your debt or budget information by contacting Customer Service as well.

You should be aware that it is not technologically possible to remove each and every record of the information you have provided from our system. The need to back-up our systems to protect information from inadvertent loss means that a copy of your Personally Identifiable Information may exist in a non-erasable form that will be difficult or impossible to locate. 3Ci promises that promptly after receiving your request, all Personally Identifiable Information stored in marketing databases we actively use and other readily searchable media will be updated, corrected, changed or deleted, as appropriate, as soon as reasonably practicable. 

## LIMITATIONS

While our Privacy Policy would cover all prospective Users, the Counselors only assist residents of the United States. Clients must have an US bank account and a US residence and each client's debts must be payable in US currency. 

## WEB BEACONS

Our Web pages contain electronic images (called a "single-pixel gif" or "Web beacon") that allow us to count page views. In general, any electronic image viewed as part of a Web page, including an ad banner, can act as a Web beacon. Web beacons are typically very small, 1 by 1 pixel size, banner like files, but their presence can be easily seen within Internet Explorer by clicking on "View" and then on "Source". Web beacons are so small in order not to use valuable space on the computer screen that is better used to display helpful content. A web beacon or cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user's computer for record-keeping purposes. We use cookies on this site. We do not link the information we store in cookies to any Personally Identifiable Information you submit while on our site.

We also use Web beacons within some of our email communications in order for us to determine if the email has been opened or not.

We also partner with third parties who use Web beacons on our site to optimize their ad-serving engine by re-marketing to users who have visited our site. They do not link their web beacons to any Personally Identifiable Information submitted on our site.

We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. We use session cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our site. A session ID cookie expires when you close you browser. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time. You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser's "help" file.

We do not set a persistent cookie to store your passwords, so you don't have to enter it more than once. Persistent cookies also enable us to track and target the interests of our Users to enhance the experience on our site. Some of our business partners(e.g., advertisers) use cookies on our site. We have no access to or control over these cookies. This privacy statement covers the use of cookies by this site only and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers. This site uses click to talk technology (also commonly referred to as push to talk and call me now) to allow Users to receive a phone call from a company representative to provide assistance. This service is provided by a third party, ATG (formerly eStara Communications), who will collect names and phone numbers from users wishing to use the service. This collection of PII is only used by eStara for the purposes of placing the outbound phone call and providing reporting to 3Ci. No collection of PII by eStara is used for marketing purposes either by eStara, or 3Ci. If you choose to not provide your Personally Identifiable Information to obtain assistance, you may contact us directly at 888-888-CARE.

If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some areas of our site, such as contests or surveys, will be limited. 

Our Web beacons do not collect, gather, monitor or share any personal information about our Website visitors, they are just the technique we use to compile our anonymous, aggregated statistics about Website usage.

## HOW WILL I KNOW IF THERE ARE ANY CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY?

If we decide to change this Privacy Policy or email practices, we will post those changes on our Website so you are always aware of what information we collect, how it is used, and under what circumstances, if any, it is disclosed. If at any point Personally Identifiable Information will be used in a manner significantly different from that stated in this Privacy Policy, or otherwise disclosed to you, at the time it was collected, we will prominently post any changes on our Website for 30 days prior to any change. We may also make non-significant changes to our Privacy Policy that generally will not affect our use of your Personally Identifiable Information. If you do not agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy, you should refrain from using our Website.

## WHO DO I CONTACT IF I HAVE ANY PRIVACY QUESTIONS?

If you have any questions about our Privacy Policy or feel that we are not abiding by the terms of our posted Privacy Policy, please contact our Privacy Coordinator by Clicking Here.

Print
